cellular-news.com 2008-05-16

# Privacy Policy - Scientific

| 

Scientific : Privacy Policy   
  
---  
  | 

PRIVACY POLICY  
  
**Scope and Purpose**

This privacy statement is designed to help you understand how Thomson Scientific (“we”) may collect and use personal information about you as a client, or potential client, of our products and services. 

This privacy statement applies to any personal information you may provide to us via Thomson Scientific’s websites (“Web Sites”). These Web Sites provide direct links to other web sites. This privacy statement does not apply to those web sites. Before disclosing personal information on any other company’s web site, you should read the privacy statement associated with that web site. 

Any information you may provide to our customer support services, whether directly or through one of our Web Sites, will be covered by this privacy statement. That information may include any personal contact information and business-sensitive information such as system information, search strategies and problem descriptions we may need to provide assistance and information to you. 

Some of Thomson Scientific’s products and services also contain personal information. This information may be embedded in the records comprised in those products or services, extracted from those records or obtained directly from the individuals. This privacy statement does not apply to that information, but if you want to find out more about how Thomson Scientific uses personal information in its products and services or ask questions or comment on any of your personal information in our products and services, please contact us using the details provided in the ‘How to contact us’ section below. 

**How we use and share your information**

We may use your business contact details to provide you with information you have requested and additional information about our products and services by mail, email or telephone. We would also like to share your details with other affiliated Thomson Scientific companies throughout the world who may similarly use it to provide you with information about their products and services. Occasionally we may pass on your details to our agents or contractors who will use it to send out information on our behalf. We will not otherwise pass on your details to any third parties. 

Where you provide us with contact, product and systems information for customer support, this data will be used only in order to provide technical support and troubleshooting. 

**Non-personal data we collect**

In general, you may browse our Web Sites without providing any personal information. Similar to other commercial web sites, our Web Sites use standard technology called "cookies" and web server logs to collect information about how the Web Site is used. Cookies are a feature of web browser software that allows web servers to recognize the computer used to access a web site. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's web browser on the user's hard drive. Information gathered through cookies and web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web Site, and the web sites visited just before and just after our Web Site. This information is collected on an aggregate basis, as you and others browse our Web Sites, is not used to identify you in any way. If you want to interact with us via the Web Site, we may ask you to provide us with some personal information. 

You can, of course, disable cookies on your computer by indicating this in the preferences or options menus in your browser. However, it is possible that some parts of our Web Sites will not operate correctly if you disable cookies. You should consult with your browser's provider/manufacturer if you have any questions regarding disabling cookies. 

**Security policy**

We take reasonable steps to maintain the security of the personally identifiable information that we collect, including limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers, as well as installing electronic security systems that guard against unauthorized access. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us, so you do so at your own risk. 

**Changes to our privacy policy**

From time to time, we may change our privacy policies. If we make a change, it will not affect the choices you have made about any information you gave us before that change. Any changes will be reflected in an updated privacy statement that will be posted on our Web Sites. 

**Complaints**

We are committed to working with you to resolve, quickly and fairly, any complaints you may have about privacy. If you have any questions to comments, or you want a copy of our Data Privacy Complaints Policy, please contact our [Data Privacy Team](mailto:ts.dataprivacy@thomson.com)

**Identification**

This statement has been provided by Thomson Scientific Limited and Thomson Scientific Inc., on behalf of Thomson Scientific, part of The Thomson Corporation. To find out more about the businesses and brands that comprise Thomson Scientific go to <http://scientific.thomson.com/brands>. 

**How to contact us**

At any time you may ask us to: 

  * Send you a copy of your information. 
  * Remove your information from our records. 
  * Correct or update any of your information. 
  * Opt you out of receiving promotional information from us by post and/or email. 

For access to, or correction of, your contact and preference information, please contact our [Data Privacy Team](mailto:ts.dataprivacy@thomson.com)
